抱歉  他吵醒你了
Sorry he woke you.
不是他
Oh, it wasn't him.
那是我又打呼噜了
Was I snoring again?
我还以为那声音是低空喷气机
I thought it was a low-flying jet.
谢谢你能陪他玩
Thanks for playing with him.
没什么的
I don't mind.
反正我也需要早起
I had to get up early anyway
还得开车回家换衣服上班呢
to drive home and get changed for work.
他是个乖孩子
He's a good kid.
我很想去你那里
You know, I'd like to stay at your place,
但是我有本杰明要照顾  所以
but when I have Benjamin, it's...
我知道  没关系
I know. It's fine.
你得小心了  女士
You should be careful, lady.
我指不定什么时候就娶了你
I could still make an honest woman of you yet.
你可以的
You actually could.
你听说上个月的政策变化了吗
Did you hear about last month's policy change?
听说了  不再限制办公室恋情
Oh, yeah. No more sanctions on office relationships.
我读了邮件
Yeah. Read the e-mail.
对啊  只要他们之间不存在等级问题
Right. As long as there's no rank issues.
也就是说  我没法和里斯本约会了
Right. So, I, uh... I couldn't date Lisbon.
没错  但你想约里斯本吗
Right. But do you want to date Lisbon?
不想  老天  我不是
No. God, no. I just--
不
No.
他们还允许探员之间结婚呢
They're even letting agents get married.
太好了
It's awesome.
你要先去洗澡吗
You want to shower first?
你去吧
Oh... you go.
好的
All right.
里斯本  太好了
Lisbon. Good.
咱们去纳帕  你来开车
We're going to Napa. You drive.
凶杀案报道
Homicide bulletins?
热点新闻
Hot off the press.
鸭塘里有具无名尸体在等着呢
A John Doe in a duck pond awaits.
听起来应该归当地警方管辖
Well, that sounds like a case for local authorities.
答对了
Bingo.
纳帕啊  等一下
Napa. Okay, wait a minute.
那是麦卡利斯特警长的管辖区
That's Sheriff McAllister's jurisdiction
你想去调查血腥约翰嫌疑人
You want to go and investigate a Red John suspect.
调查是你的事
Investigating is your thing.
我只是想去多了解一下他
I'd just like to get to know him a little better.
走吗
Shall we?
加利福尼亚  纳帕谷
加州  纳帕谷  贝拉维斯塔教堂
园丁发现尸体沉在池塘底下
Gardening crew found the body submerged in the pond.
看起来他泡水里还没几个小时
Doesn't look like he was in the water for more than a few hours.
头骨后方有重击伤痕
There's a contusion on the back of the skull.
可能是被人从背后偷袭
I'm guessing someone caught him from behind.
他在深更半夜的
What was he doing behind a church
在教堂后面干什么
in the middle of the night?
个人物品呢
Any personal belongings?
没有发现钱包和手机
No wallet or cell phone.
只有前兜里有些钱
Just a money roll in his front pocket.
32块零钞
$32 in small bills.
简
Hey, Jane?
有什么想法吗
Care to offer your opinion?
这些鸭子很喜欢吃松饼
These ducks love muffins.
你帮了"大忙"了
Very helpful.
看他们游了
Look at 'em go!
游骑兵们来了啊
I see the cavalry has arrived.
麦卡利斯特警长
Sheriff McAllister.
里斯本探员  什么风
Agent Lisbon. What, uh...
什么风把您这精英小组吹到我们这小地方来了
What brings your crack team to our little slice of heaven?
你知道的  就找个借口来见识下葡萄酒乡
Oh, you know, any excuse to get up to Wine Country.
指北加州种植葡萄的地区
好吧  我们很欢迎有人来帮忙
Well, we always welcome the help,
但是我认为我可以处理好这件事
but I expect I can handle this one.
实际上
Well, to be honest, it was uh
是我想要来的
It was me that wanted to come out here.
-是这样啊  -我有个感觉
- Is that a fact? - Well, more of a feeling.
这里的事件不那么简单
I think there's more out here than meets the eye.
怎么说
How so?
-你没感觉到  -没有
- You don't feel it? - no.
你有什么发现
What's your take?
发现什么
On what?
死者的事
Our friend.
我们来看看吧
Well, let's have a look.
1 5 6
"One five six."
他会不会是推销员  这是他的代码
You suppose he's repping his code?
1-5-6是电话销售人员用的地区代码
Area code 1-5-6 is reserved for telemarketers,
所以应该不是
so I'm guessing no.
他看起来是那种工作懈怠的人
Well... he's kind of a slack-looking fella.
光看尸体都觉得他前途无望
Gloomy, even for a corpse.
廉价的服饰  也没啥肌肉
You know, cheap clothes, no muscle tone.
低收入的办公室白领
Sedentary low-income job.
应该是这样
Sounds right.
该你了
Your turn.
鞋底纹理集中在脚跟部
The tread on his shoes wrap up around the heel
为了防止脚跟打滑
to prevent the heel from slipping,
与很多赛车手一样
Like those of a serious race car driver,
或者是一个假装会赛车的快递员
Or a delivery man that likes to pretend he races cars.
如此这般  加上他兜里
Couple that with the roll of small bills
找到的零钱
found in his pant pocket...
披萨送货员
Pizza delivery man.
也可能是送墨西哥菜或肋排的
Could be Mexican. Or ribs.
可能
Could be.
但是  你没闻到
But, uh... you don't detect
他身上有股淡淡的牛至味道吗
the faint scent of oregano about him?
这是个大线索
That's a leap.
■
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：丁  面条打包子  王小麦  Michael  壹不贰  那时花开
超感警探
第六季
第三集
■
时间轴：兜兜兜爹  Sagelibra   校对：灰灰是菇凉  狂舞之鹤
第六季
第三集
■
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   精校&总监：灰灰是菇凉
有什么想法
What do you think?
他没有看上去的那么笨
Well, he's not as dumb as he looks.
他是血腥约翰吗
Well, is he Red John?
有点言之过早
It's too early to say.
我们要怎么查啊
How do we find out?
我需要和他单独在一起
I need to be alone with him.
这可不太明智
Well, that would not be wise.
在搞什么呢
What's cookin' in here?
找到什么线索了吗
Spot any clues?
没有
No.
不过你看到那个锤子没有
Well, just that hammer up there. You see it?
它锤头上沾的是不是血迹
Is that blood on the hitting side?
可能是的
Could be.
我叫人来取证
I'll call forensics.
伙计们
Fellows?
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
他不想去爬梯子
He did not want to go up that ladder.
那个心理医生不是说过
Didn't the psychiatrist's office say
血腥约翰怕高吗
that Red John was afraid of heights?
很机智啊  里斯本
That's very astute, Lisbon.
火眼金睛
Well observed.
他们搞完外边的事就会过来
They'll join us when they're done outside.
我等不了那么长
Yeah, I can't wait that long.
警长  你能爬梯子上去拿一下吗
Sheriff, would you mind going up the ladder for me?
你想让我穿着这种尖头靴子
You want me to climb all the way up there
去爬那么高的梯子吗
in these pointed toe boots?
没合适的鞋子可不行
That's a job for sensible shoes.
最好能帮我这个大忙
It would be a big help.
我来吧  头儿
I got it, boss.
谢谢你  孩子
Thank you, son.
老大  周在车管所的系统里找到了死者的指纹
Hey, boss, Cho got a D.M.V. hit on the victim's prints.
他叫拉里·金凯德
His name is Larry Kincaid,
46岁  无犯罪记录
46, clean record.
看起来不是血  应该是油漆
No. Doesn't look like blood. I think it's paint.
谢了  瑞斯比
Thanks, Rigsby.
金凯德住在瓦卡维尔市
Kincaid lived in Vacaville and worked
职业是一名披萨送货司机
as a pizza delivery driver.
受害人在纳帕做什么
What was the victim doing in Napa?
他的老板说他是来参加他侄女今晚的婚礼的
His boss said he was here for his niece's wedding tonight.
史黛丝·邦纳
Stacey Bonner.
晚宴彩排昨晚在这里举办的
The rehearsal dinner was here last night.
好吧  你俩待在这边
All right, you two stay in the area
找找目击证人
and look for witnesses.
我们去那婚礼派对看看
We've got a wedding party to find.
加利福尼亚  纳帕  七仙女酒厂
用桌子来帮你摇晃红酒  桌子是你朋友
Use the table to help you swirl. The table's your friend.
你这动作真性感
You look so sexy when you do that.
这样做能将氧气带入红酒中
This draws oxygen into the wine
散发出酒的芳香
to bring out the aroma.
谁在乎它闻起来什么样  喝吧
Who cares what it smells like? Let's drink.
打扰一下  这是邦纳和萨拉斯的婚宴吗
Excuse me. Uh, uh, is this the Bonner-Salas wedding party?
我是史黛西·邦纳  有什么事吗
I'm Stacey Bonner. Can I help you?
我是加调局的特蕾莎·里斯本探员
Yes, I'm Agent Teresa Lisbon with the CBI.
这位是派翠克·简
This is Patrick Jane.
今早我们在贝拉维斯塔婚礼教堂后面
We found a body behind the Bella Vista Wedding Chapel
发现了一具尸体
this morning.
是出席你婚宴的客人
It's a member of your party.
他叫做拉里·金凯德
His name is Larry Kincaid.
拉里舅舅  不要啊
Uncle Larry? Oh, no.
没一个人掉眼泪啊
Don't everyone cry at once.
邀请我妻子的弟弟只是出于礼貌
My wife's brother was something of a courtesy invite.
他是个好人  但是
He's a nice enough guy, but...
不太通人情世故
a little off, socially speaking.
好吧
Okay.
我想你是新娘的父亲
Uh, you're the bride's father, I take it.
那你的妻子在哪
And, uh, where's your wife?
她回酒店休息了
She's resting back at the hotel.
她昨晚开始犯偏头痛
She came down with a migraine last night.
可怜的拉里舅舅  妈妈一定会崩溃的
Poor uncle Larry. Mom's gonna freak out.
没事的  亲爱的
It's okay, carino.
婚礼被毁了
The wedding is ruined!
他是怎么死的
What happened to him?
我们正想要查明这一点
That's what we're trying to find out.
我能看下尸体吗
Can I see the body?
苏西  你这样不太合适
Suzie, that's not very appropriate.
这就是生活啊
This is life happening.
我们不能消极躲避
We can't shut our eyes.
那  我能看看他吗
So... can I look at him?
不行
No.
在死者生前  谁最后一个见过他
Who was the last person who saw the victim alive?
我们所有人  在彩排晚宴后
All of us. After the rehearsal dinner,
我们都想去大的派对帐篷
we all hit up the big party tent.
那叫婚礼礼篷
The wedding pavilion.
是婚礼礼篷
The wedding pavillion.
就是教堂旁边那个大帐篷
It's the big tent by the chapel.
当时酒喝完了  拉里主动提出去拿酒
We ran out of wine, and Larry offered to make an alcohol run.
我是萨拉斯先生  罗伯托是我儿子
I'm Mr. Salas. Roberto's my son.
后来拉里舅舅回来过吗
Did uncle Larry ever come back?
没有  但我们也没觉得奇怪
No. But we weren't surprised.
还以为他是想找个借口离开派对
It felt like he was looking for an excuse to leave the party.
没错  就好像他
Yeah. It's like he was...
在做鬼之前已经像鬼一样游荡了
a ghost before he was a ghost.
安格尔  你个蠢货
Angel, you're such an idiot.
他可是她舅舅
He was her uncle.
很抱歉  亲爱的  他看起来人还不错
I'm sorry, baby. He seemed like an okay guy.
我不是为了拉里舅舅哭的
I'm not crying about uncle Larry.
是为了婚礼的事
It is the wedding day.
我们还是会结婚的  对吧  对吧
Hey, we're still gonna get married, right? Right?
也许吧  但一切都太令人沮丧了
I guess. But it's all so... sordid.
好啦
Yeah.
里斯本说这是死者生前
Lisbon said this was the last room
最后待过的屋子
the victim was seen alive in.
这将会是场很美的婚礼
Well, it's gonna be a beautiful wedding.
想要花钱  我能想出更好的方法
Eh, I can think of better ways to spend good money.
是吗  比如说呢  新的皮组合沙发吗
Oh, yeah? Like what? A new leather sectional?
不是
No.
好吧  你怎么猜到的
Okay, how'd you guess?
我以前一直梦想着能有个灰姑娘一样的婚礼
I used to dream about having a Cinderella wedding.
真的吗  你从没提过
You did? You never said anything.
很久以前的事了
Ah. It was a long time ago.
现在听起来肯定挺傻的
I suppose it all seems silly now.
我们是警察
Police.
谁在里面
Who's in here?
慢慢走出来
Step out slowly.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
把它放下
Set it down.
把手背到身后
Hands behind your back.
不是你们想的那样
It's not what you think.
这是什么
What's this?
在结婚蛋糕里加泻药吗
Laxatives in the wedding cake, huh?
-真是为人着想啊  -你叫什么名字
- That's a cute move. - What's your name?
奥斯卡·萨拉斯
Oscar Salas.
新郎的弟弟
The groom's brother.
你为什么想要破坏你哥哥的婚礼  奥斯卡
Why'd you want to ruin your brother's wedding, Oscar?
为什么不呢
Why not?
你不喜欢他的未婚妻吗
You don't like his fiancee?
她是个刷推狂  超级自恋狂
Twitter freak. Completely self-obsessed.
他们都是  像每时每刻都需要别人关注的小孩
They all are. Children who need constant feedback.
等他们吃了那个蛋糕
Just wait until they try that cake.
我真是等不及要看他们的推特了
I am dying to read that tweet.
拉里舅舅人怎么样
What about uncle Larry?
他看起来不错
He seems cool.
至少他跟别人不一样
At least he doesn't follow the pack.
你知道昨晚在彩排晚宴之后
Did you know he was murdered last night
他被谋杀了吗
after the rehearsal dinner?
不知道
No.
你知道谁有可能想伤害他吗
Any idea who might want to hurt him?
有  安格尔
Yeah. Angel.
我哥哥的伴郎
My brother's best man.
他一直在不停说拉里的坏话
He talked trash about Larry all the time.
他好像还给拉里发过短信
I think he sent him text messages, too.
你对死者有什么不满
What was your beef with the victim?
没有不满
No beef.
我们听说你不喜欢他
We heard you didn't like him.
你们听错了
You heard wrong.
我对他一点想法都没有
I didn't have no opinion of him.
跟他不怎么熟
Barely knew the guy.
我们还听说你通过短信刁难过他
We also heard you harassed him with text messages.
那不是真的
That's not true.
不如你把短信让我看一下吧
How about you show me those texts?
我不会把手机给你的
I'm not giving you my phone.
我在半小时内就能搞到法院指令
I can have a court order here in 30 minutes.
只不过那时  我将视你为嫌犯
Only then, I'll be looking at you as a suspect.
"拉里  你老板那边有消息了吗
"Hey, Larry, any word yet from your boss?
我真的很需要那份工作  谢了  伙计"
I could really use the work. Thanks, buddy."
他在帮你找一份披萨店的工作吗
He was helping you get a pizza job?
我需要工作  那又怎样
I need work. So what?
-你得到那份工作了吗  -没有
- You get the job? - Nope.
在彩排宴会之后的派对期间
Did you leave the wedding tent at any point
你离开过婚礼帐篷吗
during the after party?
没有  我一直待到结束
No, I was there till the end.
不信你去问别人
Ask anyone.
在我离开的时候  拉里早都没影了
And Larry was long gone by the time I left.
多谢你前来  邦纳夫人
Thank you for coming, Mrs. Bonner.
你有没有看到你弟弟离开派对
Did you happen to see your brother leave the party?
没有  我当时头疼
No, I, uh... I had a headache.
我就提前离开了派对
I left the party early
走回了蜜月套房
and walked back to the honeymoon suite.
为什么你住在蜜月套房里
Why were you in the honeymoon suite?
这个婚礼的钱都是我们付的
We're paying for this wedding.
死者在派对上都做了些什么
What was the victim doing at the party?
没什么特别的
The usual.
站着  在一旁看
Standing... watching.
说实话  我觉得他还挺可怜的
To be honest, I felt sorry for the man.
你和死者是什么关系
What was your relationship with the victim?
拉里是我未婚妻的舅舅
Larry's my fiancee's uncle,
所以在我看来  他就是我的亲人
so as far as I'm concerned, he's my blood.
但这个亲人很古怪
But weird blood, you know?
你知道有什么人想要伤害死者吗
Do you know of anybody who may have wanted to harm the victim?
没有人跟他很亲  但也没人跟他交恶
Nobody really felt strongly enough about him
都挺平淡的
one way or the other.
他就好像  跟大家都不亲
He just kinda... floated along
游离于家族之外
like family flotsam.
他有那种能力
That was his strength, you know?
那种在社交中不引人注目的能力
The power of social invisibility.
我想我可能会爱上他
I think I could have loved him.
在派对上他跟什么人说话了吗
Did he talk to anyone at the party?
对  我儿子在大学认识的朋友  查理
Yes. My son's friend Charlie from college.
你知道罗伯托上过大学吗
Did you know Roberto went to college?
我们家里头一个
First in the family.
我那时已经喝高了
Well, I was pretty toasted.
我记得拉里那时在谈论一把新步枪
But I think Larry was talking about a new rifle.
他说他买来自卫的
Said he bought it to defend himself.
步枪  你确定吗
Rifle? Are you sure?
死者没有枪支所有记录
The victim doesn't have any record of gun ownership.
我觉得他只是想要融入圈子
I think he was just trying to fit in.
想成为一分子才这么说的
You know, be one of the guys.
所以他才会主动提出去给我们买酒
Same reason Larry offered to go on a liquor run for us.
你有看到死者离开派对吗
Did you see the victim leave the party?
我不会说英语[西语]
No hablo inglés.
稍等一下
Excuse me.
婚礼上一定有人看到了什么
Somebody in that wedding party had to have seen something.
空气中充满了爱意  里斯本
Love is in the air, Lisbon.
这两家人就要联姻了
These two families are about to be married.
不推他们一把他们不会出卖对方的
They're not gonna turn on each other without a push.
怎么推
What kind of push?
要查出谁杀了拉里舅舅
If we want to learn who killed uncle Larry,
我们要做到以正视听
then we need to clear the air.
也就是说不要再为了新人装友善了
That means no more playing nice for the happy couple.
你们要诚实
We need some honesty.
-谁不诚实了  -首先是你
- Who's not being honest? - Well, you, for starters.
你应该是新郎的姐姐吧
You're the groom's sister, I take it.
也是我的伴娘
And my bridesmaid.
这么做本来挺好的
Yes, that was a lovely gesture,
但是这样反而会让她尴尬
but you put her in a very awkward position,
-因为她讨厌你  -我没有
- because she resents you. - No, I don't.
你有  诚实点
Yes, you do. Be honest.
你讨厌我吗  罗丝
Do you resent me, Rose?
你对我弟弟颐指气使  总是指正他
You talk down to my brother! You're always correcting him.
那不是真的  她什么时候
That's not true. When has she ever--
别说话  罗伯托
Not now, Roberto.
罗丝  你生气是因为
Rose, are you mad at me
我帮你付了伴娘礼服的钱吗
because I paid for your bridesmaid dress?
你可没付我的礼服的钱
You didn't pay for my dress.
你又不是售货员
You don't work in retail.
现在她对我这么做了
Now she's doing it to me.
史黛西学的是英语专业  丫头
Stacey was an English Major, Chica.
她只是讲起话来有点高傲而已
She just sounds superior.
"丫头"  我女儿可不是你家里的佣人
"Chica"? My daughter is not your housemaid.
她会说英语
Hey. She speaks English.
你们能不能互相尊重一下彼此
Can we all show some respect here, please?
我们是一家人了
We're a family now.
是啊  幸福的一大家子
Yes, one big, happy family.
所以你才在彩排后的派对上和新娘的妈妈
Is that why you hooked up with the bride's mother
勾搭到一起是吗
at the after party?
你说什么
What was that?
你说你妻子昨晚偏头痛
You said that your wife had a migraine last night,
说大概是喝多了
which is the enablers' code for "drunk."
而今天  她都不敢直视新郎的爸爸
And today, she can't look the groom's father in the eye.
所以今天早上她才没去品酒
That's why she wasn't at the wine tasting this morning.
你居然对我妈下手
You made a move on my mom?
你怪我爸干什么  也许是你妈才是奸夫
Why are you blaming papi? Maybe your mom's the adulterer.
-是奸妇  -别纠正他了
- Adultress. - Stop correcting him!
我现在发现了
Yeah! I see it now.
闭上你的嘴
Okay, shut up!
今天是我结婚  我想说什么做什么
This is my wedding day, and I will say and do
都是我说了算
whatever I want.
而我要
And what I want...
取消婚礼
is to cancel this wedding.
生活啊  充满了意外
Life. Happening.
史黛西  你那是气话
Stacey, you don't mean that.
你们为这场婚礼准备了几个月了
You guys have been planning this for months.
我从佛罗里达飞过来参加你们的婚礼
I flew in from Florida to be here.
你自便吧
You're all on your own.
这招推得不错
Nice push.
会有好进展的  你很快就能看到了
Ah, something good will come out of this. You'll see.
-可以回纳帕了吗  -请吧
- Can we go back to Napa now? - Please.
新郎的弟弟说
Groom's brother said
双方家庭都不赞成他们结婚
that neither side of the family approves of the wedding,
但他们都装作赞成
but they're both pretending like they do.
现在可不装了
Not anymore.
我跟进了那条步枪的线索
I followed up on that rifle tip.
根据银行记录  拉里舅舅
According to bank records, uncle Larry wrote
两周前用个人支票买了枪
a personal check for one two weeks ago.
我们需要枪支销售商的联系方式
We need contact information for the firearms dealer.
一个私人牧场主卖给他的
A private rancher sold it to him.
叫詹姆斯·哈里斯  我有他的地址
James Harris. I have an address.
死者说买枪是为了保护自己
The victim said he brought a rifle to protect himself.
我们查查看是为了防谁  瑞斯比  跟我走
Let's find out from who. Rigsby, you're with me.
我会对婚宴受邀名单上的人做背景核查
I'll run background checks on the invitation list.
我还以为你是来破案的
I thought you were supposed to solve a crime,
而不是破坏婚礼
not, uh, destroy a wedding.
那是凶手干的
Well, I'd say the killer did that.
我等着惊叹你敏锐的洞察力了
I'm prepared to marvel at your insight.
谁是凶手
Who's the killer?
还在查
Still working on it.
是吗  我这下真的吃惊了  我还以为
Really? I'm surprised. I'd have...
我还以为你现在应该已经抓住他了
I'd have thought you'd have him in cuffs by now.
抱歉让你失望了
Oh, I hate to disappoint you.
简  邦纳夫人想和你谈谈
Jane. Mrs. Bonner would like to have a word with you.
你说得对
You were right.
我离开派对之前  和萨拉斯先生接吻了
Before I left the party, Mr. Salas and I shared a kiss.
一个喝多了以后错误的吻
A drunken, mistaken kiss.
你们是在哪里醉吻的
Uh, where did this, uh, inebriated smooch take place?
教堂后面
Behind the chapel.
你们有看见池塘边有什么动静吗
Did you see anything here by the pond?
没有  但是午夜前后我们有听见水溅声
No, but we heard a splash around midnight.
有听到任何尖叫  或者挣扎的声音吗
Did you hear any... screams or sounds of a struggle?
我应该去帮他的
I should have gone to help him.
那也没什么用
It wouldn't have mattered.
他是在其他地方被杀害的
It seems he was killed someplace else.
只是被抛尸在此而已
The body was just dumped here.
凶手把尸体藏在池塘里  等到婚礼结束
Hiding the body until after the wedding in the pond,
要我说  这池塘可不是藏尸体的好地方
which is not such a great hiding place, I would think.
太不隐蔽了
A little too public.
贝拉维斯塔
Bella Vista.
教堂名为音译  实意后有解释
贝拉维斯塔
Bella Vista.
意大利语美景的意思
"Beautiful view" in Italian.
这里的美景在哪儿
Where is this, uh, bella vista?
穿过树林
Through the trees.
这才是抛尸的好地方
Now this is a place to dump a body.
好好看看
Take a look. Huh?
凶手把尸体拖到池塘边
Killer hauls the body to the pond.
再多走几步
Just a little bit further,
就可以把尸体抛在这里了
and he could have dumped it right here.
他说的对  那里什么都没有
He's right. Nobody's finding anything down there.
过来伙计  来看看
Come over here, fella. Have a look.
不用了  我很熟悉那里的景色
No, I'm familiar with the view.
跟我们说说我们在看什么
Uh, tell us what we're looking at.
抱歉  我要回这个
Excuse me. I'm gonna take this.
第二次了
Strike two.
你现在相信我了吗
You believe me now?
周  你觉得我适合结婚吗
Hey, Cho, you think I'm a marrying type?
你跟孩子他妈求过婚了
You proposed to your baby mama.
是啊  因为每个孩子都应该有一对父母
Well, yeah, but every kid deserves two parents.
我是在说范佩尔
I was talking about Van Pelt.
-你把她肚子也搞大了吗  -没
- You knock her up, too? - No.
那为什么会说到这个
So why are we talking about this?
你一定没看到局里的内部通知
Well, you clearly missed the departmental memo.
他们修改了办公室恋情的规定
They changed the policy on office relationships.
不用再遮遮掩掩了
Don't have to lay low anymore.
那很好啊
Good for you.
如果我们想  我们甚至可以结婚
We could even get married if we wanted to.
哦
Ah.
就这样吗  "哦"
That's it? "Ah"?
她想结婚  可是你不想
She wants to get married and you don't want to.
才不是  也许是吧
No. Maybe.
不是  我不知道  你觉得我该怎么做
No. I don't know. What do you think I should do?
你想让我来担责任吗
You want to make it my fault?
你说得对
Okay, you're right.
我该自己决定
It's my call.
你们是在私人土地上
You're on private property.
我们是加调局探员  你是詹姆斯·哈里斯吗
CBI agents. You James Harris?
是的
That's right.
你大概两周前卖了一把步枪给一个
You sell a rifle to a man named Larry Kincaid
叫拉里·金凯德的人吗
about two weeks ago?
很有可能  我得查查收据
It's quite possible. I'd have to check my receipts.
你未经许可贩卖枪支
It's a violation of state law
违反了本州的法律
for you to sell firearms without a license.
你的谷仓里藏着什么
What are you hiding in the barn?
我的私人军火库
My private arsenal.
请把门打开
Open the door, please.
把手放在我们能看到的地方
Keep your hands where we can see them.
如果我没记错
If I recall,
拉里买过一把这样的枪
Larry bought one of these.
一把1840年产斯普林菲尔德步枪
A genuine 1840 springfield musket.
现在只能放空枪
It's rigged up to fire blanks now.
你是搞模拟内战的
You're a Civil War re-enactor.
是的  纳帕谷坎伯兰郡警卫队
That's right-- Field Commander
战地指挥官
for the Napa Valley Cumberland Guard,
第156团的
156th Regiment.
我们下周在海角堡有一场战役
We got a battle next week in Fort Point.
死者衣服上的156肯定是指这个
That must be what the "156" meant on the victim's shirt.
什么死者
What victim?
拉里昨晚被谋杀了
Larry was murdered last night
就在贝拉韦斯塔教堂后面
behind the Bella Vista Chapel.
很遗憾
Very sorry to hear that.
你知不知道有谁想伤害死者
You know of anyone who may have wanted to hurt the victim?
天啊  不知道  拉里人很好
Oh, God, no. No. Larry was a harmless sort.
不爱说话  但是个好兵
Quiet, but... a good soldier.
他的离去对我们这个小部队来说
His loss is gonna leave a real whole
是个很大的损失
in our little community.
你弄坏了就得买
You break it, you buy it.
别理我  请别因为我停止祈祷
Oh, please, don't stop praying on my account.
我不是在祈祷
Oh, I'm not praying.
在教堂里  发短信
Texting. In church.
这不是罪过吗
Isn't that a sin?
希望不是  我还靠这双手吃饭呢
I hope not. I make my living with my thumbs.
很抱歉揭露了你妻子
I'm, uh, sorry for busting your wife.
这不是她第一次
It's not the first drunken kiss
酒后跟别的男人接吻了
she's shared with a man that wasn't me.
而且我也知道不会是最后一次
And I'm sure it won't be the last.
你知道谁杀了她弟弟吗
Do you have any idea who killed her brother?
我想应该是婚礼上的人
I believe it was someone from the wedding party.
不  不  你错了
No. No, you're wrong.
没人会杀拉里
No one had any reason to kill uncle Larry.
就像没人会杀  美洲驼一样
It would be like... killing a llama.
为什么要杀它们呢
Why would you?
它们乱吐口水
They spit?
你是干什么的
What do you do for a living?
我是个投机商
I'm a speculator.
我搜寻价值被低估的资产
I look for undervalued assets.
哪类的
What kind of assets?
艺术品  岛屿
Oh, artworks, islands--
只要我能低买高卖就行
anything I can buy low and sell high.
上个月我在一个教堂拍卖会上
Last month I found a first edition
发现了头版的《卡佛岱尔圣经》
Coverdale Bible at a church auction,
1535年史上第一个完全翻译成现代英语的圣经版本
1535印刷的
printed in 1535.
本来打算在婚礼上诵读上面的一段
I was gonna do a reading from it at the wedding.
值多少钱
How much is that worth?
五十万吧
Oh, uh, half a million.
就买了一本古老的圣经
For an antique Bible.
它现在在哪
Where is it now?
在一家私人保安公司
With a private security firm.
他们会在今晚婚礼时送来
They were gonna deliver it here for the wedding tonight.
或许应该现在就卖掉它
Might as well just sell it now.
我是范佩尔探员
Agent Van Pelt.
格蕾斯  我需要你帮个忙
Grace, I need your help.
这对新人必须要按计划
It is imperative that our young lovers
进行他们的婚礼
go ahead with the wedding as planned.
可能吗  你毁了那个女孩的婚礼
Good luck with that. You ruined a girl's wedding.
是的  我没法抚平他们心理的创伤
Yes, and I lack the putty to spackle those emotional wounds.
所以我才找你
That's why I'm calling you.
我有办法
I have putty?
不  你有人生经验
No, you have life experience.
用你的经验说服新娘
Use it to convince the bride
她的"幸福人生"会从今晚开始
that her "happily ever after" begins tonight.
不是吧
Really?
简对发生在候审室里的事
Jane is feeling really badly
感到十分抱歉
for what happened in the bull pen.
没必要
He shouldn't.
我们走不到一块  他还帮了我个大忙
This was never going to work. He did me a huge favor.
你的家人不想让你们结婚
Your families don't want the marriage.
妈妈说罗伯托配不上我
Mom says I'm too smart for Roberto.
爸爸担心他没有能力照顾我
And my dad is worried he won't be able to take care of me.
而罗伯托的父母想让他娶一个
And Roberto's parents just want him to marry
信天主教的女孩
a nice Catholic girl.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我想要罗伯托
I want Roberto.
但是
But...
太复杂了
it's too complicated.
所以你要放手了
So you're gonna throw it away?
听我说
Look...
我也有想要一起度过下半辈子的人
I had someone I wanted to spend the rest of my life with.
但是  我们在一起意味着我要放弃工作
But... staying together would have ended my career.
所以我放手了
So I let him go.
怎么了
What happened?
我跟别人订婚了
I got engaged to someone else.
结果却很不好
That ended badly.
所以我开始封闭自己的内心
So I shut down a little inside.
这样让我感到更有安全感
Closed some doors to feel safer.
但是
But...
问题是  随着时间流逝
the problem is with every passing year,
你关上的心门越来越多
you close more doors.
直到最后
Until eventually...
你都不知道会不会有人能走进你的心
you wonder if anyone will ever get inside again.
-太悲哀了  -是的
- That's really tragic. - Yeah.
所以我还留着那套裙子
Well, that's why I keep the dress.
你的婚纱
Your wedding dress?
我知道这很傻  是吧
I know. It's crazy, right?
但是
But...
它提醒着我  我以前是怎样的
it reminds me of who I was...
天真  可能还有点傻  但是
Naive. Maybe a little foolish, but...
内心充满希望
full of hope.
我担心如果我扔掉婚纱
I'm afraid if I destroy that dress...
我就会忘记希望是什么滋味
I'll forget what hope feels like.
麦卡利斯特那边怎么办
What are we gonna do about McAllister?
除非我能跟他单独相处一段时间
Well, until I get some alone time with him,
否则我得不出任何结论
I'm not gonna draw any conclusions.
他两次都不想上高处
Well, he's avoided heights twice.
如果血腥约翰恐高
If Red John is acrophobic,
他为什么要告诉我的心理医生
why would he tell my shrink?
为了获得她的信任从而偷走她的文件
To gain her trust so he could steal her file--
杀她之前他也的确这么做了
which he did right before he killed her.
你们猜怎么着
Guess what?
我们要结婚了  没有不愉快了
We're getting married. No hard feelings.
我觉得这个决定很好
Well, I think that's a great decision.
恭喜你们  当然
Congratulations. You-- of course, you know,
我们也得出席婚礼
we will have to attend the ceremony,
以防杀死拉里的凶手出现
just in case uncle Larry's killer reveals himself.
-好的  -你们应该跟着我们
- Okay. - Uh, you should follow us.
-法院关门了  -法院
- The courthouse closes. - Courthouse?
你们不是在纳帕举行婚礼吗
What about your big Napa wedding?
是有点可惜  但是又能怎么样呢
It's a waste, but, I mean, what can we do?
我找不到牧师  早上我叫他不用来的
I can't find a priest. I canceled him this morning.
而且教堂也只能再用两个小时  所以
And we only have the chapel for two more hours. So...
知道吗  其实我是一个
Well, you know, it turns out that I am, in fact,
有资质的婚礼司仪牧师
a certified wedding officiant.
-我可以给你们主婚  -我的天
- I can marry you. - Oh, my gosh.
-真是大救星啊  谢谢  -太感谢了
- You're a lifesaver. Thank you. - Thank you so much.
是我的荣幸
It would be my pleasure.
你才没有资质呢
Oh, you are not legally ordained.
我有  只是从没用上
Yeah, I've never used it.
我常觉得有一技傍身很方便
But I always thought it was a handy thing to have.
我才不信呢
I don't believe you.
我发誓  我一分钟之内就能让你结婚
I swear. I could marry you off in a minute.
嗨  罗恩
Hey, Ron.
别试探我
Don't tempt me.
我是麦卡利斯特警长
Sheriff McAllister.
我是派翠克·简
Yeah, it's Patrick Jane.
有事吗  派翠克
What can I do for you, Patrick?
我在教堂这边  案子有突破了
Well, I'm at the chapel. We have a break in the case.
你多久能赶到这里见我
How soon can you meet me here?
非常快
Real soon.
真有趣  我在停车场看到你的车
Funny thing, I, uh, saw your car in the lot,
我刚好要来找你
and I was just coming to find you.
没听到你的脚步声
I didn't hear you coming.
你走路很轻
You move quietly.
老习惯了
Well, it's an old habit.
我这大半辈子都在打猎
I've been a hunter most of my life.
真的吗  你都打什么
Really? What do you hunt?
长脸的我都打
Anything with a face.
就是消遣嘛  对吧
Game is game, right?
-你打猎吗  -我吗  不打
- You hunt? - Me? No.
我有洁癖
No. Too squeamish. I--
我搞不了剥皮开肚那种事
I couldn't handle all the skinning and the gutting.
是啊
Yeah. Sure, yeah.
要收拾猎物把它大卸八块
Clean and quarter a kill.
的确要有点胆量
It takes some stomach for that.
还得嗜血
And a certain bloodlust.
这话有点道理
There's a grain of truth in that.
鸭塘案有突破了是吗
So you got a break in the duck pond killer case?
与其说突破不如说是计划
Well... less a break, but, uh, more a plan.
我今晚要揭露凶手是谁
I'm gonna reveal the killer tonight.
我需要你和你的人
And I need you and your people
先别插手
to just hang back.
没问题
No problem.
很感激你让我的工作变得这么轻松
I truly appreciate you making my job easier for me.
你真美
You look great.
谢谢夸奖  韦恩
Thank you, Wayne.
简觉得凶手会中途溜出宴会
Jane thinks our man's gonna try to sneak out of the reception.
我们要守在那  我会跟着他
We need to be there. I'm gonna follow him.
如果他太小心不敢行动怎么办
What if he's too cautious to make a move while we're here?
如果他在婚宴这边
If he's in the reception tent
待了超过两小时
for more than two hours,
简希望你们能弄点小插曲
Jane wants you to create some sort of distraction.
他觉得会让凶手有胆子溜出去
He thinks it'll encourage him out.
什么样的插曲啊
What kind of distraction?
别担心
You know what? Don't worry.
我来搞定
I can handle this.
很好  很好  分头行动
Great. Great. Let's split up.
"因此人要离开父母
"for this thing shall a man leave his father and mother
与妻子连合
and cleave unto his wife,
二人成为一体"
and the twain shall become one flesh."
听起来有点乱啊
Whoa. That sounds messy...
但也很美
but beautiful.
谢谢  邦纳先生
Thank you, Mr. Bonner.
为我们朗读稀有又贵重的
Reading from the very rare
《卡佛岱尔圣经》中的内容
and valuable Coverdale Bible.
圣经读了
Scripture--tick.
戒指  已经交换完了
Rings--we've, uh, we've done that.
你以前干过这事吗
Have you ever done this before?
你呢
Have you?
当然  我结过婚
Yes. I'm married.
下一步是什么
What's next?
接吻
Kissing.
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
如果没人反对的话
If there are no objections...
没有
Nope, okay.
根据法律赋予我的权利
By the power vested in me--
通过网络授予我的圣职
by a mail-order ministry--
我宣布你们正式结为夫妻
I... I now pronounce you husband and wife.
罗伯托
Roberto...
你可以亲吻新娘了
you may kiss the bride.
小心保管
Be careful.
可以的话我帮你保管吧
I'll guard that for you, if you'd like.
想得美
You wish.
邦纳先生把它交托于我
Mr. Bonner trusted me to lock this away
婚宴时把它锁到神父的房间里
in the priest's room for the reception, so...
一边去吧  小子
Step back, son.
抱歉
Excuse me?
谢谢  尝尝蛋糕吧
Thank you. Try the cake.
太谢谢了
Oh, thank you.
已经两个小时了
It's been two hours,
连一个接近出口的人都没有
and nobody's going anywhere near the exit.
得来点插曲了
We need a distraction.
我看起来怎么样
Okay. How do I look?
还不错  怎么了
Fine. Why?
那就好
Good.
抱歉  话筒开着吗
Excuse me? Is this on?
打扰一下  女士们先生们
Uh, excuse me, ladies and gentlemen,
请给我一点时间说两句
can I have your attention, for, uh, one second, please?
我还想再给新人送上一段祝酒词
I'd like to offer one more toast.
我想感谢史黛西和罗伯托
I'd like to thank Stacey and Roberto
让我明白保护梦想
for making me realize just how important it is
有多么重要
to protect a dream.
我没有保护好自己的梦想  说实话
I didn't protect my dream. To be honest,
我不知道该怎么做
I, uh, well, I didn't know how.
但是当你在错误的时间碰到对的人
But what can you do when you meet the right person
你能怎么办呢
at the wrong time?
照样搞她
Do her anyway!
当然这也行
Well, yeah, that works...
可那是暂时的  但是
for a while. But...
最终有些话你说了
Eventually you say things
又或是没说出口
or don't say things.
犯的错自己都数不清
You, uh, make more mistakes than you can count.
到了最后
And in the end,
一切分崩离析
things fall apart.
这就是你说的小插曲吗
Is this your idea of a distraction?
相信我
Trust me.
如果你足够幸运
Now if you're lucky,
你们也许又会找回彼此
you might find each other again.
但是有太多往事和心痛的事
But there's too much history and heartache
阻挡你回到梦想身边
to ever find your way back to that dream.
起码我之前是这么想的
At least that's what I thought.
我希望
I'm hoping...
我想错了
I was wrong.
格蕾斯
Grace...
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
说点什么吧  这是真的
Well, say something. This is real.
我愿意  韦恩  我当然愿意嫁给你
Yes, Wayne. Of course I'll marry you.
目标行动了
Target's on the move.
真够容易的啊
Oh, that was easy.
你怎么知道我会来
How'd you know I'd be here?
在局里吵架的时候
You know, the big fight at the CBI,
只有你希望婚礼
you were the only one that wanted
如期举行
the wedding to go ahead as planned.
因此  你才是那个有罪的
Ergo, you were the guilty party.
有罪  我只是查看一下圣经
Guilty? I was just checking on the Bible.
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
-你杀了人  -什么
- You killed a man. - What?!
查理别狡辩了  你这是在让自己难堪
Oh, Charlie, stop. You're just embarrassing yourself.
能用油灰刀撬开门栓的
There's only one way you could jimmy a dead bolt--
方法只有一个
with a putty knife.
你锯断了门闩
You sawed through the bolt.
你从派对溜出去
So you snuck out of the party,
但是有人抓了你的现行  对不对
but... somebody caught you in the act, didn't they?
查理
Charlie?
你在这里干什么  拉里
What are you doing here, Larry?
我来偷神父的酒
I came to swipe the priest's wine.
派对的酒喝光了  挺聪明吧
We ran out at the party. Pretty smart, huh?
你在这里干什么
Uh, what are you doing here?
你手里的是锯吗
Is that a saw.
你想偷圣经  对不对
You're gonna steal the Bible, aren't you?
你知道这东西的值多少钱吗
You know how much that thing is worth?
拉里  它上过保险的
Larry, it's insured. All right?
邦纳先生会拿到赔款  我们也会发财
Mr. Bonner will get his money, and we'll get rich.
这样吧  我让你也入伙
That's right, I'll cut you in.
你这辈子都不用送披萨了
Okay, you'll never have to deliver another pizza in your life.
我其实挺喜欢送披萨的
I kind of like delivering pizzas.
我回派对了
I'm going back to the party now.
拉里  等等
Larry, wait!
你不会告发我吧
Well, you're not gonna tell them, are you?
不会
No, I--
我回去而已  再见
I'm just going back. Bye.
我觉得你不是蓄意要杀他
I don't suppose you wanted to kill him,
不过事与愿违
but, uh, if wishes were horses,
覆水难收
and all that...
你不是本地人
And you not being from around here,
不知道那边有悬崖
you didn't know about the cliff,
就把尸体丢在池塘里了
so you threw the body in the pond.
你把钱包和能证明身份的东西拿走了
I suppose you took the wallet and I.D.
是想伪装成抢劫的样子吧
because you wanted to make it look like a robbery.
把油灰刀放下吧
You can put down the putty knife now.
算了
Whatever.
还是让我的律师来处理吧  只是
I'll leave this up to my lawyers. Just...
别把手铐铐太紧  行吗
Don't make the handcuffs too tight, okay?
-铐手铐这事不归我管  -简  闪开
- Oh, no, no. I don't do the cuffing... - Jane, move away!
查理  把枪放下
Charlie, put the gun down.
我爸死在了监狱里
My dad died in jail.
我可想呆在外面  劳您费心
I'll take my chances on the outside, thank you.
你现在把我放了
You know, if you just let me go,
事情肯定还有商量的余地
I'm sure they'd be happy to open the dialogue with you.
查理  冷静
Charlie, stay calm.
你不会想自寻死路的
You don't want to go down this road.
对  你不想的
No, you don't.
都走远点
Get away from me!
想活命吗  带我离开这儿
You wanna live? Get me out of here.
上楼  快  走
Upstairs, now! go!
查理  想想你在做什么
Charlie, think about what you're doing!
-门后是哪里  -不知道
- What's through the door? - No idea.
这儿有我
I'll cover it.
你和瑞斯比  范佩尔去外围包抄
Set up an exterior perimeter with Rigsby and Van Pelt,
同时呼叫支援
and call for backup.
往前走
Keep moving.
我也想走  查理
Uh, yeah, I'd-- I'd love to, Charlie,
可我没长翅膀
but without wings--
上屋顶  快
On the roof. Now!
-我们得离开这儿  -好吧
- We're getting out of here. - Okay.
你知道有从这儿下去的路吗
Uh, you know if there's a-a way down from here?
我们能找到路下去的
We're gonna find a way down.
就怕你这么说
Yeah, that's what I was afraid of.
把枪放下
Drop the gun.
这下他可以见到耶稣本人了
Now he's talking directly to Jesus.
你从哪儿上来的
Where-- where did you come from?
教堂为了修剪树木架了把伸缩梯
The church keeps an extension ladder for tree trimming.
别往下看  在这儿晕了可不好
Don't look down. Bad place for the spins.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
走吧
Let's go.
你让我别插手  还好我没听你的
Good thing I ignored your request to stay away, huh?
我可能觉得自己有责任照看好你吧
Guess I just felt obliged to keep an eye on you.
是吗  这话怎么说
Yeah. Why?
事实上  我不信任你
Truth is, I didn't trust ya.
你硬要来插手这个案子
The way you forced your way onto the case here--
我简直觉得你有什么阴谋
it almost seemed like you had a hidden agenda.
有时候我容易让人会错意
Ah, well, sometimes I give out mixed messages.
我这人的众多缺点之一
It's one of my many failings.
-看来大家都没事  -当然了
- It looks like everybody's okay? - Sure.
他在那边屋顶上救了我的命
He saved my life out there on the roof.
应该的
My pleasure.
随时效劳
I'm at your disposal anytime.
我们楼下见吧
I'll see you two downstairs.
走开  走开
Hey, get it out! get it out!
真没想到
I didn't see that coming.
最讨厌这些东西
I hate those things.
你没受伤吧
You're not hurt?
我没事  里斯本
Oh, I'm fine, Lisbon. Ha.
你错过了好戏  知道吗
Well, you missed all the action, you know.
是吗
Oh, I did?
你没见我在屋顶上的样子吗
Did you not see me out there on the roof?
-那才叫好戏呢  -不是这回事
- That was some action. - This is different.
我们可能要比预期
It looks like we're going to be spending
在纳帕多呆几天
a little bit more time in Napa than we expected.
是吗
Really?
请面对彼此牵手
Join hands and face each other, please.
格蕾斯  你先说
Grace, you'll begin.
跟我重复
Repeat after me.
-我格蕾斯  -我格蕾丝
- I, Grace... - I, Grace...
-愿意你韦恩  -愿意你韦恩
- Take you, Wayne... - Take you, Wayne...
做我的丈夫
to be my husband.
从今往后  相互拥有  相互扶持
To have and to hold from this day forward...
无论是顺境或是逆境
For better or for worse,
富有或贫穷
for richer or for poorer,
疾病或健康
in sickness and in health,
彼此相爱相惜
to love and to cherish...
直到死亡将我们分开
until death do us part.
看来你都记熟了
You seem to have that down.
我早就等着这一天了
This has been a long time coming.
轮到你了  韦恩
And now you, Wayne.
就如她刚刚所说的
Uh, everything she just said.
格蕾斯
Grace...
不会再浪费时间了
No more wasted time.
我要和你共度每一天
I want to spend every day with you.
无论未来怎样
Every day for the rest of our lives
我们将共度余生
and... whatever comes after.
无私的爱没有起始与终结
Love freely given has no beginning or end.
你们的戒指将代表你们对彼此无止尽的爱
Your rings represent your unending love for each other.
请把格蕾斯的戒指递给我
May I have the ring for Grace, please?
谢谢
Thanks.
把戒指戴上格蕾斯的手指
Place that ring on Grace's finger
同时请跟我重复
and repeat after me.
这枚戒指代表我对你的爱
I give you this ring as a symbol of my love.
格蕾斯  这枚戒指代表我对你的爱
Grace, I give you this ring as a symbol of my love.
以此戒指为证  我与你缔结婚姻
With this ring, I marry you.
With this ring... I marry you.
请把韦恩的戒指递给我
May we have the ring for Wayne, please?
我想你知道怎么做了吧
I think you know what to do.
是的
Yeah.
韦恩  这枚戒指代表我对你的爱
Wayne, I give you this ring as a symbol of my love.
以此戒指为证  我与你缔结婚姻
With this ring, I marry you.
鉴于你们双方均渴望
Inasmuch as the two of you have made known
并同意结为夫妻
your mutual desire and your consent to be married,
依据我被赋予的权力
by virtue of the authority invested in me,
我宣布你们成为夫妻
I hereby pronounce you husband and wife.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
抱歉没给你想象中的童话般的婚礼
I'm sorry it's not the fairy tale you dreamed of.
只要我愿意  每一天都是童话
I'll take the real thing any day.
二位
Hey, guys...
你们去酒店的马车备好了
Your ride to the hotel is ready.
还有马车吗
We have a ride?
我们有马车
We have a ride.
21响礼炮  列队
21-gun salute! Formation!
准备
Ready!
瞄准
Aim!
放
Fire!
我们该出发了
I think that's our cue.
准备
Ready!
瞄准
Aim!
放
Fire!
准备
Ready!
瞄准
Aim!
放
Fire!
新婚